Hello, the Fundamentals training set in
plain language has been made available to the Frachart site for public and free use.
I hope it will be of interest to you. Hello
and greetings to you, dear friends. Good time,
I hope you are well. I
am Alireza Madadhi. I am at your service with the third part of the Fundamentals training set
in plain language. In this part, we want to
talk about inflation,
get to know inflation a little more and get acquainted with its good and bad features, and
see why
inflation is of great importance to us in the financial markets. My friends, I have one
thing to tell you. At
the beginning, I will probably tell you the basic and basic topics in the initial parts,
this part and the next part, that is, until the
fourth part,
these topics may not be very useful in the financial market, that
is, whether we
have an understanding of inflation or the economic growth of the
economic wheels. This may
not help us in trading itself, but it will be very useful
for the next steps.
What are the next steps? For example, some data comes in,
economic data in the calendar, which
we have the data, economic data that we have to take a
good look at. These
basic and basic topics  If we
don't understand the economy, we don't have a proper understanding of the
continuity of economic data and their effect on
financial markets. That's why these are very
important. But we haven't yet entered into the topics that are
directly related to trading, which we
will get to later. Well, in this section, we
want to talk about inflation. Inflation can be defined as
price growth, meaning prices are growing.
Deflation can also be the opposite of inflation or
price decline, meaning you can
consider, for example, a scenario where the price of a
product of a car has decreased from the previous month or the
previous year. This is called
deflation and is the opposite of inflation. Guys, we need to
learn English terms because we are
working in international markets and
as a
trader, one of the events that you are going to have to deal with every month
from now on is the
central bank meetings and
their impact
on the market.
For example, Mr. Powell, the chairman of the US Federal Reserve, is
speaking in English and at that moment, if you
watch his live speech, you are much ahead of
someone who is reading his Persian translation. So
learning these is very difficult.  It doesn't get
better over time. I explained it in the previous session. I
explained it in the previous video. So inflation means
that prices are rising, and deflation
or
negative inflation means that prices are falling.
Guys, inflation, if we want to say where it starts,
the issue of inflation and how it is formed is from the
imbalance between supply and demand. Supply and demand are the forces
that drive the economy. Well,
all sectors of the economy work with price and demand.
And if demand in the economy is
higher than supply,
prices will grow. For
example, we have 5 pens. 5 people
want to buy this pen from us.
So, we set the price at 100,
for example, 100 tomans. We sell it for
free. Now, what if we
have 10 buyers for 5 pens? Then, what happens? Then, the
market becomes competitive. And
we sell that pen to whoever pays more money.
So, more demand from more buyers
causes prices to rise. Or, if we look at it from the other
side, what happens in the discussion of supply?
If there is a shortage of goods in the
economy, its price  It increases. Suppose
that dairy products are scarce and cannot be found. The value in the economy
decreases. What happens? The price of dairy products increases.
Suppose that due to a shortage of chips,
for example, in 2020, one of the things that
happened was that due to a shortage of chips, the
production of cars in Taiwan decreased.
This caused the price of cars and
used cars to increase. So inflation is due to the
imbalance of supply and demand. And this is very important.
Now, in the monetary policies of the central bank, we
talk about how the central bank
controls inflation and how it controls
demand and
inflation with the tools it is influencing. So inflation for children
means that either supply exceeds demand
or demand exceeds supply. One of these is out of balance
and
one is more than the other. If
demand is greater than supply, the price
increases. Now, for any reason, whether demand increases
or supply decreases, whichever of these
scenarios happens, the price increases.
If
demand is less than supply, the price
decreases. For example, if
we say that a good in the economy increases in value.
The price drops to a fever or when
the demand for a product decreases, the price decreases.
Suppose again, for example, suppose that
people reduce the demand for fruit. So what
happens? A farmer and a fruit seller who
is active in the fruit market is
willing to sell the fruit at a lower price so that it does not spoil.
So the decrease in demand
causes the price to drop. Or on the other hand, if you
assume that the country's fruit production has increased and
has experienced very good growth this year,
what causes it to be an abundance of fruit and
the price to drop? So
inflation goes back to the problem of demand and that
one of these two is
more than the other.
Now the next point is that we have two types of
inflation. Guys, we want to
talk about the types of inflation. We have two types of inflation:
money demand or demand-side inflation or supply-
side inflation. You probably hear these two inflations a
lot in the market. Their
names are: whether our market is money demand, whether
demand has caused inflation or supply-side inflation, or whether inflation
is due to supply. Now each of these is again
made up of several things and can be  They are
affected by different factors,
for example, in the discussion of demand-pull inflation,
what is inflationary expectations?
What does inflationary expectations mean? It means that consumers expect
prices to rise.
If you expect prices to rise, you
try to buy the product you want faster so that the
price doesn't go up.
So what happened? So that the price of the product doesn't go up?
I expect inflation. So that the price of the product does
n't go up, I'll go buy that product.
What causes this to increase demand?
Increased demand causes prices to
increase. So one of the parts that
can cause demand-pull inflation
is inflationary expectations. The second thing is increased
spending. Spanning means that people
increase their spending for any reason. Now that the
economic outlook is good or, for
example, the government has reduced taxes.
In circumstances where they increase spending anyway, that
is, they create more demand in the
economy. More demand in the
economy causes sectoral inflation.
Demand is created, prices go up.
Guys, one thing that exists is that with
inflation, demand is affected,
either going up or
down, and supply cannot
catch up with demand very quickly. For example, if we assume that the
demand for cars has increased by 10, it is
difficult to increase the supply of cars by 10. So usually, this
imbalance between price and demand shows itself in the price,
meaning that the demand that is affected is
that the company, supplier, or
manufacturer cannot react very quickly. It
cannot increase its production by 10. It does not have the capacity to
increase its production by, for example, 220.
So this equilibrium between price and demand is disrupted,
and the price moves. Now it either
goes up or down. This was the point that I
should have mentioned here. Now the next thing is the
increase in income. Income,
meaning that income in the fashion of people goes
up, causes them to spend more,
meaning they spend more money, and the
increase in spending causes demand inflation.
Let prices rise. Guys,
think about the reverse scenarios as well. For
example, this wage increase can cause
positive inflation. A wage decrease can also cause
demand to decrease and cause prices to fall.
Or, for example, a decrease in spending or a decrease in
inflation expectations can cause
prices to fall. Now, the examples I'm giving are
related to the export sector, meaning
price increases. But we also have the opposite.
We can give examples for that and reverse all of these. This can be
one of the reasons that can
cause negative inflation or price decreases. So, demand-pull
inflation. How does demand-pull inflation
happen? If
demand shifts in any way,
demand either goes up or down.
Anything that increases or
decreases demand causes demand-pull inflation.
So, so far, we've been introduced to the demand for money. We've
given a few examples of the
common factors that cause demand-pull inflation.
Now, let's move on to the supply-pull inflation.  The
supply side means that it is because of the
supply side that inflation has either increased or decreased or
decreased or
become negative. Prices have either increased or decreased.
What is the example we can give for it? I am a
consumer. Guys, we can discuss the cost of
production here.
What is the cost of production? It is
made up of different parts. We
have a product that has a production cost.
A commodity is consumed. A raw material is
a cost incurred by the manufacturer to
produce that product. And if the cost of production
increases, it causes the producer to
raise the price of his product. For example, let me give
you an example. For
example, suppose that the cost of labor
in the economy increases. This means that the producer
has to pay his labor more money.
This causes his production cost to increase. He
has to pay more wages. The cost of production increases
and causes the price of
his product to increase because he cannot afford to lose money.
In any case, the cost of that product has a higher cost
and the consumer price must
go up. So,
we said that the increase in cost here, for example, the wages of
employees, the labor of workers, causes the price of the
product to increase.  If the price of the product increases, it
causes inflation to rise. So, one of the
things is the change in the cost of production. Now,
we can also consider the price of raw materials.
For this sector, for example, I say oil.
If the price of oil increases, it directly
affects the cost of
production. So with the increase in the price of oil,
electricity, or gas, the cost of production
increases and
supply-side inflation occurs. That is, it is the producer and the
supplier who changes the price.
For example, we can give an example of the 2002 war between
Russia and Ukraine. There was a sharp increase in the price of oil, gas,
and electricity in Europe and European inflation
reached 8.0% in the UK, and even 10.0% in the UK. This is
supply-side inflation. That is, because the cost of
production has increased
[music],
inflation in the agricultural sector has occurred. Prices. The
growth in oil prices also indirectly
affects inflation. For example, due to the
decrease in transportation costs or the increase in
transportation costs, it can affect inflation. The
cost of transporting the fuel that
ships consume. All of these
affect the final price of products. For example, we
had a problem in 2021 and caused  There was inflation,
it was the supply chain that increased the cost of transportation. The
supply chain means that
a product goes from a point of production to the
consumer. It goes through several rings and
several stages. Each
of these stages, which
are part of the supply chain, can affect the final price. What
happened in
2021 was that the cost of transportation had
increased sharply, and inflation had
occurred. Another thing that
can affect supply inflation is the amount of
production. Again, I will give the example of the shortage of
chips in 2021. The shortage of chips
caused the production of cars to decrease
and the price of cars to increase. And
again, you can use this as an example of the opposite
to reduce
inflation, reducing inflation or reducing prices.
Guys, I will add one point here.
You, these things that I am saying here, I
try very hard to explain simply, to explain something
that is useful to the trader, but if you are
interested, you can find more information
by searching.  In my opinion, the
best way is to learn everything I
learned myself, that is, by
searching and
following other traders, other banks. You can
search, for example, on Google, you can
search for "inflation, inflation, and its types." You
can find a lot of articles about this inflation. You can
study it more deeply. It is
definitely effective
and
can be good for you. The
more information you have, the
better. Because guys,
in the financial markets, I do
n't want to prolong the discussion too much. I just want to
tell you this point as far as I can remember. We
sometimes encounter different factors in the financial markets,
for example, the war between Russia and
Ukraine. If you don't have enough information
about the Russian economy, about the
Ukrainian economy to some extent, now I say
superficially. You don't want to go too deep into what the
Ukrainian economy is, what they do, what they produce,
and what impact they have on the world. Not very much.
But for example, knowing that Ukraine is one of the
largest producers of lats in the world, or Russia is the
same way, and the war between Russia and Ukraine caused
food prices to increase, and this
showed itself in the global economy.  The inflation rate
showed that if you don't
know that Russia and Ukraine are food producers, you
can't analyze it properly when it happens. So the
more you read, the more you will have an inquisitive mind. It will
definitely be useful for you. Let me give you another
example. In 2016, the
Brexit issue, the British exit from the
European Union. If you don't know what Brexit is and
what is going to happen, if you
don't know the British and European economies, you won't be able to
understand its impact on prices. So additional information
can definitely be useful and go for it.
But let's move on to the types of
inflation and
whether inflation is harmful or beneficial or in what way.
Well, we have four types of inflation that I haven't
found the Persian synonym for now.
One is the Crepin Offensive or inflation below
3D. Walking Offensive Inflation is between 1 and 7. Ranin
Offensive Inflation is inflation between 10 and 20. Hyper Offensive Inflation is inflation
above 20. These are the types of inflation that we
can now determine the inflation range in which we are and say that
inflation is
beneficial and good for every economy now, but when inflation increases, it
is harmful for the economy. Well, in
Iran, we have a problem that  We have been dealing with it for 50 years. It
is inflation. Chronic inflation. It can be
said that the solution has been found in the world. How to
control this inflation and
lower prices. But Iran has a record of inflation for
50 years. It experiences hyperinflation or inflation above 20. Low
inflation is good for the economy. High inflation
is not harmful and can
cause problems. What is the benefit of inflation?
We said good inflation, low inflation. 3. What
governments are looking for, they want to
create this inflation in their economy. They
are looking to stimulate inflation and
keep it between 2 and 3. What is the benefit of this
inflation? It increases inflation expectations
and increases
inflation expectations. What does this mean? When we know that we
have a small inflation in the economy,
that small inflation causes me to
come and
make that purchase sooner. So here, the increase in
inflation expectations creates demand
and demand causes economic growth
in the economy. So now we understand why. We understand why.
Governments seek
low inflation and why it is beneficial for the economy is
because it creates demand in the economy and
demand causes economic growth.
We have another issue that is
very important in the economy and in the monetary policies of the
central bank and we
will talk about it a lot in the future. It
is the inflation-wage cycle. Guys, if inflation increases, it
causes people as
consumers, as people who are present in the employment market, to
seek to
increase their wages so that they can
maintain their purchasing power. That is, increasing
prices causes an increase in
wages in a way in the economy.
Or let's say that the consumer or the employee
expects his wages to increase or
quits his job to go to a job that
has a higher wage. If prices go up and
wages increase, the increase in
wages itself causes demand to
arise again and prices are stimulated and
move up again. So a cycle is
created here. With the increase in prices,
wages increase. With the increase in wages,
demand increases and prices increase again.
We are
very much in this cycle of wage inflation.  We are dealing with the monetary policies of the
central bank. We can say that this point in this scenario
in inflation is where the central bank sees inflation
as stable and stable, meaning inflation
that can continue. This cycle
can also increase prices and wages.
But what is the harm of inflation? First, let's
talk about high inflation. Guys, the continuous increase in prices, and
especially if inflation is above 100, a walking option, a run option,
10 to 20, a hyper option,
above 220. If inflation
is above the head, this causes people's purchasing power to
decrease. The decrease in people's purchasing power causes
economic growth to decrease. Or we can
say that the real demand of the economy
decreases. So the continuous increase in prices has this harm
to the economy. Now there is a point here.
Guys, for example, it happened in 2021 and 2. In
most developed countries, inflation
was above 5. In the United States, New Zealand,
Australia, the United Kingdom, the European Union, Canada,
almost all countries experienced inflation above 5.5. Let's
say that this happens intermittently.
We cannot say that this economy
always has high and harmful inflation. That is, we can
say that inflation in the year  In 2022 and 2021, due to the
issue of Russia and Ukraine, the sharp increase in
energy prices increased very much at a certain point,
and well, we cannot say that
developed economies have chronic inflation, bad inflation,
harmful inflation. This did not happen. Usually,
in the long term, developed economies like the
United States and the European Union have a inflation rate between zero and 3,
and this is
good for their economies. And when inflation went above 3 and we saw the losses of inflation in the economy, central banks stepped in and started to control inflation. So now, what is the loss of negative inflation? High inflation is harmful for children. We say that in
Iran, we have been seeing with our own eyes the
effect of high inflation on people's lives for years. We see
what it is like on the economy. Now, what is the loss of negative inflation?
Negative inflation is also harmful for children because the
decrease in prices makes people unwilling to
consume. Suppose again, I
say, another example: we want to
buy a car, prices are falling, the price of a car
is falling, so why should I go and
buy this car now? Wait.  I will buy in another month
when the price is lower, so
there is no desire to consume in negative inflation in the economy,
and this is detrimental to the economy. Decreasing
prices cause the desire to buy to decrease. Decreasing the
desire to buy also causes
negative inflation to become more negative and negative, or
prices to fall lower and lower, which
is even harder for the central bank to control than positive and high inflation.
That is, central banks that experience negative inflation have a
much harder time doing their job than
banks that have inflation, let's say up to 10.
So that's all about the types of
inflation and its disadvantages. Now let's go back to the
cycle that we talked about in the last session.
Let's bring our economic cycle, our growth cycle, and
add inflation to it.
Usually, inflation increases or decreases a little later than economic growth. It
usually goes like this, meaning that first growth is
affected, then
prices change, go up or down,
and then now, if we want to complete this phenomenon,
then
employment follows.  The third
factor is employment. So inflation also has a cycle
and
we see its growth and decline in economies.
And now in the future videos of the future sessions, we will give a
detailed example. We will open the monetary policies of the
central bank and concepts that
will be more interesting and directly related to trading.
Now, we want to have a table, guys,
and put economic growth next to inflation, the factor of the
tour in this table, and we will know the types of
economic cycles here, which
can be said to be used a lot in the market.
Central banks use it, traders
use it, and it
directly affects market fluctuations.
Guys, put it in this table. I
will put the pen in this
table. On the
horizontal axis, we have inflation. Well, the further to the
right we go, the higher our inflation is, and the further to the
left we go, the lower our tour is. And on the vertical axis, we
have economic growth. The
higher the economic growth is, the better it is, and the
lower it is, the negative it is. So here we
have a graph that has both economic growth and
inflation. For example, if we have an economy here
whose conditions are like this, inflation is
The economy is low or, for example, here the economic growth is
high and
inflation is
nice. Understand the table and then
get familiar with these terms. Or here if we
have an economy that is at this point, the
economic inflation is also high. Well,
now, children, we have an economic cycle
that we are going to make more complete. From the first session of
economic growth, we only talked about growth and recession.
Now, we are also learning the names of different cycles and the
names of different phases of the economy. So, you
can
say that we have a state for the economy from the perspective of
economic growth and inflation, which are like this.
The first is optical growth or desirable economic growth,
where we have very good growth, we have positive growth, we
have low inflation. Now, I will not say
negative, low inflation. The second is the rebound, the
rebound, high inflation, economic growth is also high.
In the rebound, we can say that the economy
reaches its peak or reaches its peak. The peak
that we said in the last session that we
have an economic cycle, that top point, we call
it the peak. We can say that in the rebound, the economy
is at its peak. Stack flash, or so to speak,
we have an inflationary stagnation, which  Stagflation, guys,
is a scenario where inflation is high and economic growth is
low. Stagflation, which
was a lot of talk in the market in 2021 and 2022, is a very
common scenario.  Some investors and traders expected
this scenario to happen and
we have the dis-flare, which is a flash scenario
where both inflation is decreasing and
economic growth is increasing. Guys, I'll complete this. The
rift is a scenario where inflation is
increasing and economic growth is increasing. I
think I'll bring this up in the next slide.
Yes, it's better to
talk about it here. So the relation is a scenario where inflation is
increasing and growth is increasing. The
escapism is inflation increasing and growth is decreasing. The
dis-flare is both inflation and growth decreasing.
And the optimism is inflation
decreasing and
economic growth increasing. And usually,
guys, our economic cycle is like this,
meaning it goes like a clock between these four
scenarios. That is, if we consider recession
as the low point of the
economy, we consider recovery as the low point of the
economy, which is in the dis-
flare cycle, meaning both inflation and growth are
decreasing. Then economic growth
improves a bit, meaning we get out of the
diff.  We enter optimal growth and then
we enter recession, meaning that both inflation increases
and growth then inflation.
The economy is in a recession. Inflation is extremely high and it is
harmful to the economy. This causes
economic growth to decrease. Inflation, then in this
scenario, economic growth is increasing and
decreasing, we enter the Fleischer stack, and then we
can enter the Fleischer design or economic recession. Now, guys, it is possible that this
cycle does not always happen, meaning that it is
not always like this that
we go
from this flash to the economic growth,
then we enter the relationship, then the section, then the
recession happens again. For example, it happens that
first from the optimal growth to the optimal growth, we enter the
relationship, then we move towards the flash design,
then the stack formation, then the relationship, then it goes back to the Fleischer structure,
then it
goes towards the optimal growth. We, guys, need to
understand these scenarios that
the economy can be involved in and then
see which direction we are going, for
example, now that we are in the Fleischer  Are
we heading towards a recession or are we heading
towards an optimal growth or are we heading
towards a stock market crash? We need to know
which direction we are heading and whichever direction our economy
goes, we have a different scenario for investing. That
is, investors in the recession
follow a style, they have an investment style,
in the stock market they are looking for a series of
other assets, in the recession they are
looking for a series of assets and money is
moving between these cycles. The
cycles that change, the cycles that are
affected by where they come from, from demand to supply,
from the monetary policies of the central bank, from the
fiscal policies of the government, which we will cover in detail in the
next videos. So guys,
these cycles are extremely important because
investing is different in each of
these cycles, that is, in each of these cycles,
we have to set up a trading portfolio that is specific to
that space. If, for example, we say in the
recession space we hold bonds in the
loss-comparison portfolio  We do it because the price of
bonds is decreasing and in this space
there is a space where the stock market is doing extremely well.
It is a space where the stock market or
risky stocks are doing very well.
So investing in the riffle is
different from the flash disk. We need to know this.
In the flash disk, which direction should we go? We
need to know this so that we can
identify the market trends in different wheels
from a fundamental perspective. In the
flash disk, when the economy is
going towards the riffle, which I drew for you here, if
we go down to the left, that is, we
reach this point, we are moving towards the riffle.
And if we move up to the right in any way
or this point is the target point, that
is, the economy is moving in this direction, we are
moving towards expansion, that is, we are moving
towards economic growth. I
tried to bring all the terms for you so that you can get
familiar with them. Because guys, when we are
in the market, for example, when the Federal Reserve
has a meeting and Mr. Powell comes to the FOMC meeting and
gives a speech,  It's almost like there's
a very high probability that
these words will be talked about, and each of these
words that Mr. Powell, as the chairman of the
US Federal Reserve, mentions will cause
significant fluctuations in the market.
So I brought all the words so that you can get
familiar with them. We were saying that in the
disinflationary environment or the environment that we are
moving towards a recession, we are moving towards a recession.
If I had stocks, for example, I would lose money. In
2000, the recession of 2008, the Great Depression of
2000, the Great Depression of 1930, 200. If I had stayed in the
stock market, I would have lost money.
So in the disinflationary environment,
we follow a different path in the market, we
follow a different scenario. The
basket has its own specific scenario.
So these wheels are extremely important, and we
mentioned them here. Now,
I will explain them to you in detail with four examples of
different economic wheels,
and don't rush, we will get to that point,
but we must definitely learn these basic topics. There
are also a number of other words that are
used.  You can use them in economics, in
articles, in speeches, in bank analysis,
anywhere you deal with financial markets.
Recovery is one of those words.
Recovery means, guys, that the economy is
improving or we are
moving to the upper right, towards higher economic growth
and probably higher inflation. The
peak is the point where we do
n't expect the economy to go any higher than that.
We call this point the peak point and the economy is probably going to
reverse its course. That is, we
hear and see a lot in economics when we say
economic peak. Economic peak. In my opinion, for example,
Mr. Powell says, for example, he says that we have passed the economic peak. We have
n't reached that point yet.
So these terms are important. Another term
is slo-down or slowing growth, which we can
say is
moving to the lower left,
moving towards recession, but not very recession.
That is, slo-down. You can say that the tone is
softer than recession. For example, in these
words, guys, there is a difference. If we
say
recession, I don't, for example, let's say that Mr.
Powell, the chairman of the Federal Reserve, comes.  Say that
recession and you compare it with this word that
says "slowdown" means that the speed of the economy is decreasing
or we are heading towards recession. It is
completely different. That is, the reaction that we have in the market to the
word "slowdown" is much greater than the
economic growth decrease or "slowdown". These are words
that I should have mentioned here and
we, guys, should learn these. We should learn them
so that we can use the fluctuations that
occur in the face of
news, in the face of central bank meetings,
in the face of speeches and news.
Now let's move on to the next slide,
where I gave you another example of these
economic regimes or the
economic scenarios that we had. There were four
scenarios here, guys, we have the
US stock market, the stock
index,
and it came in four cycles. It said
what the stock market conditions were like that led to
high economic growth, low inflation. It was
explained here. It means high growth, low inflation. It is
green, the
pale green that you see, guys. Whenever
we were in the scenario of increasing growth and decreasing inflation, the
stock market grew. Growth, growth, stock market, growth,
stock market.  Growth, growth, growth, growth, growth,
everywhere, we saw economic growth, stock market growth,
when growth went up and
inflation went down,
well, RF here should have
been RF, here's the wrong picture, interesting, yeah, RF
here is AF, AF or the dark green,
we see increased growth and increased inflation side by side,
which you can see again. The stock market in
this scenario, guys, has grown. The
stock market has grown. So guys,
when economic growth is up, inflation is up,
economic growth is up, inflation is decreasing,
usually the stock market has performed positively. Now,
SS happens when economic growth is down,
inflation is rising, or that Stack
Fleischer space, what happened in Stack Fleischer? The
stock market has declined. The stock market here
can be said to have suffered. Here, it has declined. Here, it has declined. Suffering.
Suffering. So, in an environment where
growth is going down and inflation is increasing,
or a Sec Fleischer space, the stock market has
not performed well. What? Those
economic recessions are when inflation is going down,
economic growth is also going down. And so
here we have stock market growth, here is a
decline, growth, here is a decline, growth, growth, and here is growth, growth,
here is also a decline.
Well, interesting point.  This is the stock market, in general,
financial markets, kids always see the future, they
price the future, they price what could
happen in the next 6 months, a year, the likely scenario ahead of us,
so why is it because of
what or a decline in economic growth, a decline in inflation, which
is our worst-case scenario, and we
call it a recession scenario? Why has the stock market sometimes grown?
Because that is the point where the market
expects support from the government and the central bank, and the
economy will probably recover and
probably return again, meaning we will have a recovery
in the economy. For example,
consider the Covid of 2002. Here, well, it was a time
when economic growth and inflation were declining.
This period, the
stock market initially fell, but then it grew.
Because it knew that we would enter the
Ordel or RAF or Optimal Growth
or Relation phase in the future, so it prices the future in the
same way in previous scenarios. For example,
in the Stack Finance space, where inflation is
increasing and economic growth is decreasing, the
market price  The recession is happening. So the
important thing is that I will have a supplementary video at the end of the
series where I will tell you some tips.
Really, market tips. One of those tips
is that,
guys, we are looking for the future in the financial markets.
No, right now, the
future of the market
will always move forward and price. They say,
buy the rumor, sell the news. That's exactly it. So let's go to the
next slide, where
I want to talk a little more about these cycles. The
growth and inflation cycle that we talked about, the riffle
sand, the esc fashion, the disfashion, the opti-gro, what does it look
like? Now, here he comes and says, in
our relationship scenario, what assets should we
buy and what assets should we sell?
For example, the US dollar, DX, and in riffle sand, the
kids are selling.
Why is it because in the riffle sand space or the
economic growth, the growth that is very significant and the
economy is probably at a very good speed, it is moving in a
very good direction? Capital is going to the
developed countries, it is going
out of the United States. Sorry, capital is
going to emerging countries, that is, from the
United States, for example.  Money is going out, it's going to
smaller economies, economies that
have higher potential for profit. In this
space, gold is declining. Why? Because there's
no reason. We can get higher returns
from other assets like stocks.
Bonds are declining in price. But for example, in the
stock market, real estate, which is the housing market, these sectors are increasing.
And sorry, the
stock market, these sectors are increasing.
These sectors are not negative. In the
stock market, the stock market is increasing in general.
In the relationship, well, as we had in the previous picture,
but again, in the stock market, we
have different sectors or different industries. The right-hand side industries or those that
can be shorted or sold
are: Helker, real estate, cancer, and
utilities. There are
a number
of industries that don't have potential. There are a number of industries that have
better conditions, for example, technology,
energy, manufacturing, and finance.
The guys in the relationship, you can buy oil, you can buy Cooper, you
can buy Egypt, you can buy the IMF fix, the same as the
countries with emerging economies.
You can see that each of these
economic scenarios has its own unique characteristics and
we have different scenarios for them. For example,
in Optimal Growth, what happens is that it is
very similar to the sand reef. It
is very similar to the relationship. But in the sand reef, for
example, let's look at the sand reef. We should
not buy oil. We should sell oil. We should not buy
industrial materials or fish.
These are stock market industries. We should
not go to
countries with higher economic growth or
emerging countries. We should go to the dollar.
We know it as a safe asset. We
should look to buy gold. In the scenario of the
flash scenario or the scenario that we said we are
moving towards a recession. Or if we
want to invest in the stock market, we
should buy health care, we should
buy utilities. So, see, each of these spaces
has its own scenario. They require their own portfolio. They
have their own investment portfolio.
We cannot go to the space of this flash with the portfolio that is for sand reef
and make a profit. This
happens.  It doesn't work, or for example, we can't go with a basket
that is for Design Flash and go to the stock exchange
and say that we will make a profit.
This doesn't happen. We need to know these things
completely so that we can make a
profit in the presence of you, the future fluctuations of the market in the coming years, the cycles that will change. Guys, fundamentals mean
that we
learn from the past by studying the past, we
gain experience so that we
can make a profit in the future. Economics is a science
that can be learned and it is not like it can
change. The wheels of the economy have always been the
same. Now, maybe we have new issues
like Russia and Ukraine, like the
Brexit issue in 2016 or the Covid in 2002.
Maybe we have new issues, but we do
n't have a new cycle. And learning the cycles,
learning the fundamentals, will
allow us to recognize the long-term trends in the market
and be able to make predictions
about which direction the market is going to go. So do
n't get tired, friends. This
was our third video, which included inflation-related cycles.  We
have reviewed the growth. I hope it was useful for you.
If the information was useful to you and you
liked this collection, share this collection with
others.
Talk about it in your friends' spaces. If you
have any questions,
you can follow our Instagram page and Telegram,
which is also a group. We also have a group on Telegram
and ask your questions there.
I am at
your service
until the next episode. Goodbye.